Guide to the Albert Burns, Robert Sproat, and Audrey Sproat collection of Laura (Riding) Jackson correspondence, 1968-1977.
Albert Burns, Robert Sproat, and Audrey Sproat collection of Laura (Riding) Jackson correspondence, 1968-1977.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Albert Burns, Robert Sproat, and Audrey Sproat collection of Laura (Riding) Jackson correspondence, 1968-1977.
6300
Audrey Sproat.
.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, dissertation, clippings, essays, typescript articles, manuscript notes, and a story.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence among Albert Burns, Robert Sproat, Audrey Sproat, and Laura (Riding) Jackson, pertaining to Mr. Burns' dissertation. Also included are a photocopy of Mr. Burns' dissertation, clippings, essays, typescript articles, manuscript notes, and a story written by Laura (Riding) Jackson.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Albert Burns (d. 1969) was the author of the dissertation "Robert Graves and Laura Riding: A Literary Partnership." Robert Sproat was his adviser at Boston University. Audrey Sproat was Mr. Sproat's wife. Laura (Riding) Jackson (1901-1991) was a poet and a critic.
This correspondence, the gift of Audrey T. Sproat, wife of Robert H. Sproat, was donated to Cornell University in 1989.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence among Albert Burns, Robert Sproat, Audrey Sproat, and Laura (Riding) Jackson, pertaining to Mr. Burns' dissertation. Also included are a photocopy of Mr. Burns' dissertation, clippings, essays, typescript articles, manuscript notes, and a story written by Laura (Riding) Jackson.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sproat, Audrey,; Burns, Albert.; Graves, Robert, 1895-; Jackson, Laura (Riding), 1901-; Sproat, Robert H.
Subjects:
American poetry--20th century.; Women poets, American.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - Albert Burns to L(R)J, Aug. 27, 1968-Feb. 1, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - L(R)J to Albert Burns, Sept. 1, 1968-Feb. 20, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Robert Sproat to L(R)J, Aug. 5, 1969-June 17, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - L(R)J to Robert Sproat, July 23, 1969-Nov. 22, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - L(R)J to Robert Sproat, Dec. 13, 1969-Mar. 19, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - L(R)J to Robert Sproat, Apr. 13, 1970-Aug. 26, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - L(R)J to Robert Sproat, Sept. 15, 1970-May 30, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - L(R)J to Robert Sproat, May 30, 1971-Sept. 16, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - L(R)J to Robert Sproat, Oct. 3, 1971-May 18, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - L(R)J to Robert Sproat, May 23, 1972-May 1, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - L(R)J to Robert Sproat, May 11, 1973-July 1, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Audrey Sproat to L(R)J, Dec. 21, 1971-Dec. 25, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - L(R)J to Audrey Sproat, Jan. 6, 1973-Dec. 19, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Manuscripts
  - "Descriptions of Planned Work," ts., 2 pp., carbon, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "A Christmastime Story," ms. 3 pp., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "A Christmas Story" [final version], ts., 3 pp., 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "A Christmas Story," ts., photocopy, 2 pp., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alternate endings, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Explanatory note for Burns and Sproat, ts. and ms., 1 p., Dec. 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Note, ms. 1 p., Aug. 2, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Critical essays and articles
  - "Robert Graves and Laura Riding: A Literary Partnership" [abstract of dissertation] by Albert William Burns, ts., 3 pp.; ts., photocopy, 3 pp., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Princeton Wins the Wild West" by Daniel N. White, [source?], clipping, pp. 8-13, Feb. 13, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Robert Graves' Debt to Laura Riding" by Michael Krikham, Focus on Robert Graves, no. 3, ts. pp. 33-44, with note by L(R)J attached, 2 pp. and second copy, Dec. 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Despairs" [author?] ts. pp. 1-18, photocopy (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Laura Riding Poems" by Michael Kirkham, from The Cambridge Quarterly 5, pp. 302-308, Spring 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "The Seizin Press" by Hugh Ford in The Private Library, second series, Vol. 5: 3, pp. 121-128, with postscript by Laura (Riding) Jackson, pp. 139-147, Autumn 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "The Seizin Press" photocopy of ts., pp. 1-19 + 3 pp., with revisions and corrections, 1 p. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "An Ambition Beyond Poetry" [no author] in TLS, clipping, pp. 151-152, Feb. 9, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Book-length projects
  - "Robert Graves and Laura Riding: A Literary Partnership," by Albert William Burns, dissertation, ts., carbon, pp. 1-206; includes notes by Mrs. Jackson, in which she mentioned restrictions that are no long in place, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Robert Graves and Laura Riding..." (cont'd), ts., carbon, pp. 207-412 (Box 3, Folder 6)